MILAN KACAR

Software & Survey Engineer



ABOUT ME

I am a Software Engineer & Survey Engineer with 5+ years of professional experience. I graduated Geodesy at Graz University of Technology in Austria, where I worked as a project and teaching assistant. Currently, I am working in the e-commerce & fintech industry for Niceshops GmbH and Gateway Ventures GmbH as a Data Scientist / Engineer / Analyst. I grew up in Mrkonjic Grad (Republic of Srpska, BA) where I finished my high school having Mathematics, Logic, and Physics at a Higher Level.

PERSONAL INFORMATION

Date of birth	01.09.1995
Birthplace	Banja Luka, BA
Citizenship	Austrian
Marital status	Single
Sex	Male
	Birthplace Citizenship Marital status

EDUCATION

GYMNASIUM

BSc Geomatics Engineering University of Technology, TU Graz

Master's Degree Programme - Geodesy University of Technology, TU Graz

Master's Degree Programme - Computer Science University of Technology, TU Graz

UNIVERSITY & PERSONAL PROJECTS

- SCIENTIFIC PAPER MINER Based on the publishing institutions we define our market competitors and geocode their locations. [Python/WebScraper]
- POLLEN TREE DETECTOR (FROM SATELLITE IMAGES) This project presents an automated tree detecting and identification method based on image processing of satellite imagery. [Python/keras/pytorch]
- STOCK PRICES PREDICTOR Project uses AI (Artificial intelligence) and ML (Machine learning) as a hybrid approach to detect prices fluctuation (SP 500, Dow Jones, DAX etc.) [Python/keras/pytorch]
- RUSHB APP New method to summon a waiter and order food in bars and restaurants. As a test page you can look at http://www.dolcevita.rushb.app/client.php. [JavaScript/PHP/Java]
- DIFFERENT SIGNAL PROCESSING PROJECTS Mostly projects on GNSS signals. [C++]
- GRAVITY ANOMALY MAPS GRACE misson. [Python/MATLAB]
- KALMAN FILTER ADVANCED KALMAN FILTER PARTICLE FILTER as a part of indoor navigation. [C++]
- DIFFERENT ARDUINO PROJECTS Mostly projects from youtube tutorials and combination of different projects. [C/Java/C++]

TECHNICAL STRENGTH

Python	••••
Google Cloud	•••••
C/C++	••••
GIS	••••
PostgreSQL	••••
Cloud computing	••••
Navigation	••••
GNSS	••••
Signal Processing	•••••
Java	••••
Data Structures & Algorithms	••••
MySQL	••••
Docker	••••
Java Script	••••
РНР	••••
Linux	••••
R	••••
Apache Spark	•••••
Scala	

Scala

DISSERTATION WORK

BSc Thesis

Database for cycling routes

- Entity Relationship Diagram.
- Building the Database.
- Conversion from analog to digital maps.

MSc Thesis

PV (Photovoltaic) panels detection from satellite images

- Project uses AI (Artificial intelligence) and ML (Machine learning) as a hybrid approach to detect panels.
- Building an independent model to work on different datasets.
- Cloud computing
- YOLOv5

WORK EXPERIENCE

Survey Engineer **GEODATA**

July 2019 - December 2020

Semmering Basistunnel, Austria

Tunnel surveying | 3D Laser scanner measurements

Teaching Assistant

TU Graz

March 2021 - January 2022

Graz, Austria

Integrated navigation | Sensor fusion | Indoor navigation

Software Engineer

TU Graz

🛗 Sep 2019 - January 2022

Graz, Austria

Software Architect | Project Management | Automation | Data Analysis | ML Forecasting | Statistics | Automotive Battery and Electric Vehicle Testing

Data Scientist & Data Engineer niceshops GmbH

Vienna, Austria

Finances (all types of tasks) analysis | Cloud computing | Looker | Al & ML tasks | Courses inside the house / teaching (Looker) | Research about demand forecasting | Dynamic pricing

Data Engineer / TL

Gateway Ventures GmbH

August 2023 - pending

Vienna, Austria

Startup Founding | Startup Valuation models | Pitch Deck Analyzer | Tinder for Investors/Startups | Data Lake construction | Data Mining | Data Scraping | Project Management

STRENGTHS

Hard-working Decision Making

Ability to Work Under Pressure

Motivator & Leader

Conflict Resolution

Time Management

Target oriented

Able to travel

Flexibility and Adaptability

Problem solver

LANGUAGES

Serbian | Croatian | Bosnian **English** German

Russian



HOBBIES



Reading

I am trying to read a book per week.



Sports Addict

At a young age I enjoyed playing tennis, but my interests migrated towards Fitness and healthy food.



Travelling

After living in a rustic, small town for the past 18 years, I was craving change and adventure. Ten years later, I've traveled to more places during college than the first two decades of my life.



Trading

I love to analyze the markets and factors that may impact the price on daily/weekly and long term basis.